look forward
to supporting this bill and we know sir
that the thousands of new zealanders
listening
as this passage of the bill goes forward
about his
to talk about that gentleman and the
labor party need for insurance right now
you can't ensure a political parties
unfortunately but this bill is all
talking about the potential
for the insurance and you can't talk
about mislaid documents and you can't
unsure for
misused uh bits of paper that could
disappear
but you can insure against other
financial misfortune mr speaker and that
that's what this bill is all about the
ability to take into account potential
uh issues in the insurance sector
because every now and again you you
might get way late or disasters may
strike
documents get misplaced things go
disastrously wrong
and then and then in that situation you
never know what might happen you never
know where things might end up
and exactly mr garrett but look i
want to talk seriously about two aspects
of this bill that seriously expects
about about the issues around the
solvency requirements
because it's very important that uh that
insurance companies are
and uh are kept solvent for kiwi mums
and dads
because you never know who may have
invested and have their money
covered in those insurance companies are
there to cover uh unaffected
circumstances like life insurance
income replacement insurance because you
never quite know when you might need
income replacement insurance and i think
there might be
some people who'd be very interested in
that right now about how safe their
money is and they can relate to
income replacement insurance policies
and i must think i'm quite relaxed about
that
i think i must say i'm quite lucky
unfortunate i'm very uh happy with my
situation
insurance at the moment my insurance
life insurance is the best with a very
safe company
and it's only going to be made safer by
this bill and i think this is a great
thing
the solvency requirements in this bill
are going to be taken into account
and improve the ability of kiwi mums and
dads to have their companies a little
bit
safer but i think i'd be a bit worried
if i was in the labor party about
maybe where their companies may be
because they take into account where it
might be
in terms of where the cup their
investments might be taken into account
and the issues of solvency whether it
invests in real estate or
other other things and the reserve banks
put in place some very good rules and to
take an account make sure kiwi mums and
dads
have their monies nice and safe in
insurance companies mr speaker i'll talk
about quickly one other thing this issue
around captive insurance companies
this bill actually allows captives to
thrive they're particularly captives
that are new zealand-based captives to
be able to operate within a regulatory
arrangement
and that's quite good for those big
companies new zealand that particularly
operate large infrastructure businesses
i know we had the infrastructure bill
earlier
and that uh these sort of companies like
to self-insure
their major assets uh through new
zealand owned and operated captives
and this bill goes a long way to assist
them to continue to operate mr speaker
and i think that's a really good thing
these are companies like particularly
big sues like solid energy kiwi rail
transport
as well as other big entities operating
in the infrastructure space and i think
that's got to be
a highly positive thing for the hard
working people who use those services to
have the trust and knowledge that
that those assets will be better and
more safely looked after because of this
bill
and this bill i think mr speaker um when
we went through uh there was some
touching on
by um the the great work that financing
spinach committee did on this bill and i
like to think my my colleague has just
actually left the deputy chair who did a
lot of the work during the submission
phases and i think
amy adams has got to be congratulated
for the work she did in that work
in that area particularly because the
chair had was quite busy doing
uh other things every now and again and
it was uh she did a very very good job
in terms of things that were going on
through the submissions there are about
50 odd submissions and we heard about 30
of those and
they were very varied and particularly
the airline pilots what i
vividly remember and i think um there
were many comments about the airline
pilots association and the worries about
they had around insurance
and the importance of those people who
fly a lot i think would be very
concerned about the issues around
the airline pilots association and the
need to make sure that they were
adequately insured so the plans can keep
flying so members of parliament
if they show choose to can continue to
travel overseas there was concerns about
that
mr speaker i'm gonna i'm gonna wrap it
up i'm gonna wrap it up there
because this bill was pretty much
self-explanatory people are comfortable
with it across the house
and it's very much unanimous exception
this is a good step in the right
direction
by the hard-working john key government
thank you
mr speaker i called stuart nash thank
you very much mr speaker